<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>deviljames.com</title>
   
   <link>https://deviljames.com</link>
   <description>A blog.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Poor Little Hysterical Witch!</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//haxan</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//haxan</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“To me, a witch is a woman that is capable of letting her intuition take hold of her actions, that communes with her environment, that isn’t afraid of facing challenges.”<br />
Paulo Coelho</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I promise myself—because no one else reads this—that I won’t spend every post lambasting religion. But, again, watched a film last night that set me to seething about its subject matter, of which religion is a prime focus.</p>

<p>That film: <em>Häxan: Witchcraft Through the Ages</em>.</p>

<p><em>Häxan</em> is a 1922 documentary/fantasy film directed by Benjamin Christensen that seeks to educate us on the history and plight of the Witch, from the dawn of time up until the then modern years.</p>

<p><em>Häxan</em> has long been a part of the esteemed <a href="https://criterion.com">Criterion Collection</a>, and is painstakingly restored via an impressive 2K restoration process and presented on Blu Ray with a handful of features.</p>

<p>This to say, it’s a film considered by many to be valuable in the cinematic canon. However, as the film settled into itself—and it’s not until part two that actual actor performances begin—I often found myself laughing <em>at</em> the film. Quite mockingly in fact. It feels campy, and the subject matter being quite far removed from our current time struck me as rather goofy. That was until I remembered: <em>holy shit, this is a documentary</em>. This isn’t meant to be comical farce. This is meant to explore the history and reality of the witch and her plight.</p>

<p>It was then that the severity of what we were watching set in. This is exposing centuries of barbaric mistreatment and misogyny toward women, predominantly at the behest of the Church.</p>

<p>For a woman to be labeled, tried, condemned and executed as a witch required scarcely anything beyond her being, say, old and ugly, or perhaps young and pretty—leaving a completely subjective and hazy line for any female to toe. All it took was someone’s accusation.</p>

<p>If merely called a witch, a woman was removed from her home and essentially tortured to the point of either admitting to things she’s never done just to stop the barbarism, or for the few strong of will, being punished for their refusal to confess.</p>

<p>Being accused—quite frankly by any fucking person in town—of witchcraft was a death sentence. The only question being how long and how painful the remaining moments of her life would be.</p>

<p>The implements of torture of the day were seemingly endless. Which brings me to wonder, who the fuck sits around and comes up with these methods and devices of torture. Apparently frightened, entitled men of “<em>faith</em>.”</p>

<p>In one scene in the film, Christensen uses artwork of the period and title cards to demonstrate one method of torture in which a woman would be bound at her hands and feet, like a cowboy might tie a hog, and then thrown into whatever body of water was nearby. Priests with long oars would ensure the woman remained face down. If she were to die and sink, meaning she was not a witch, the priests would praise their god for her soul having been saved. If she refused to sink, meaning obviously she’s a witch, she would be removed and burned at the stake.</p>

<p>In another scene, this time with performers, Christensen takes us on a tour of what it might look like, from start to finish, for a woman to be declared a witch and thusly dealt with. In this scene, a young woman’s husband has fallen ill. We learn that he had grown dizzy, and the most logical of conclusions for this malady was that the poor man was cursed by a witch—certainly it couldn’t have been that he worked hard in the midday sun and failed to hydrate. Or, happened to catch whatever fucking other myriad sickness of that day that essentially ate life away from millions.</p>

<p>Nope. Had to be a witch.</p>

<p>As <em>Fate</em> would have it a poor and elderly woman comes to their home and asks for something to eat. The young lady provides food, but is perturbed by the old woman’s wrinkles and deep set eyes. Certainly this is her witch. Long and short, church men take her away and torture her to the point of confession and dispatch of her as well as all the other women she was forced to name. Irony of ironies, the young woman who set this all in motion…she was named a witch by the old lady and she as well was dispatched accordingly.</p>

<p>What I find compelling about his film is how it illustrates a subject I’ve long been drawn to, that being what I refer to as the <em>Fear and Myth of the <strong>Other</strong></em>. Be that <em>Other</em> race, gender, creed, sexuality geography, age, etc. those unlike us become ever so easily subjected to our prejudices, and as this film explores, have for centuries upon centuries now.</p>

<p>Perhaps the fear of <em>Otherness</em> is simply an inherent human trait. I personally don’t like that idea at all. I find life far more flavorful and exciting because there are so many <em>not</em> like me. How and why so many are scared of different cultures and ideas is beyond me, and also grossly fascinates me.</p>

<p>Theistic religions are at their core an exclusive ideology. You’re either of their ilk, or you’re not; you’re an infidel. Most of these religions seek to allay that <em>Otherness</em> via proselytizing; through <em>conversion</em>.  But make no mistake, if the <em>Other</em> does not become like them, they’re useless to them. (Again, even I admit that I know many religious folk—be they Christian, Muslim, etc—that aren’t awful, racist, sexist, homophobic, misogynistic people…but they’re exceptions to the rule.)</p>

<p>Ultimately with the benefit of decades of hindsight, we learn that what men and women of the times of the Middle Ages called a witch was often no more than a widower or a young woman who’d not found a husband, or sadly, perhaps a woman born with a mental or physical malady. The true crime? These women were not only shunned by their community, but destroyed by it.</p>

<p>Here we are in the Common Era year of 2020, and while we may not drag women from their homes to test their buoyancy before burning them at the stake, we still don’t universally treat them as equals. Women are still blamed for their own assaults, be those random or domestic partnerships. If not blamed, certainly they are held to bear the burden of proof. Women are still assumed to be the homemaker and the caretaker. They’re still expected to leave their pursuits and desires behind to nurture their family; whereas, a man should be just as willing and capable.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/haxan2.jpg" alt="That tonguey devil..." /></p>

<p>As Coelho alludes above, the witches of our day aren’t covered in ointment and licking the asshole of the devil in a cemetery any more than they were in the days of the Salem trials. Witches then and now are simply women with more desire in their heart for their own growth and strength than that of subservience and the fortitude to pursue anything otherwise.</p>

<p>And it’s only feeble little men—commonly shrouded in “<em>the cloth</em>“—that are frightened by that notion.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Poor little hysterical witch! In the middle ages you were in conflict with the church. Now it is with the law.”<br />
— <em>Häxan</em></p>
</blockquote>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Irresponsibility of the Afterlife Myth</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//no-afterlife</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//no-afterlife</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Being a Humanist means trying to behave decently without expectation of rewards or punishment after you are dead.”<br />
— Kurt Vonnegut</p>
</blockquote>

<p>They say if you don’t want to make a stink steer away from religion and politics. Well, I’m here to make a stink.</p>

<p>I don’t dare say that I’m so enlightened that I am in complete focus upon the <em>here and now</em>; however, I do focus on life. <em>This</em> life. And in doing so, I cannot help but feel enraged and at times helpless against the seeming futility of my ability to affect change upon what I see as a lost and destructive culture of capitalistic greed. We don’t even have to look to the elite to see atavistic greed’s impact upon our land or our people. It’s as if the ascent to becoming a <em>Have</em> somehow divests one of the memories of having been a <em>Have-Not</em>.</p>

<p>Here in <em>‘Merica</em>, where Capital is king, it’s frustrating to see a society of indifference toward our most valuable of all assets; human life (<em>once it’s vacated the womb, that is</em>) and this planet. This is not exclusively an American issue, I know that, but the American experience is my experience, and so I speak from that point of view. For decades industry has pillaged our land and people through politicized actions like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eminent_domain"><em>eminent domain</em></a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surface_mining"><em>strip mining</em></a>. Forcing both people and wildlife out of their homes for the sake of short-term profits for a very few.</p>

<p>My slice of this country is often referred to as <em>The Bible Belt</em>, and for good reason. The populace of this region is easily manipulated by simple plays on their myopic and misunderstood theologies; hand-me-down rhetorics they can barely cite for themselves. While I personally detest theistic religion, I concede that not all religious folk (here, being predominantly Christian) are <em>bad</em>, just as not all Republicans are bad. In fact, almost certainly no person is <em>all bad</em>—nor all good for that matter. However, the Christian and the Republican have joined in a sort of political marriage here in the West. And behind closed doors, that marriage has invited in a poisonous bedfellow, <em>Big Industry</em>.</p>

<p>The Christian may not know about the liaison the Republican has with Industry, but I wager it’s less the not knowing and more likely the not acknowledging. See, I can’t speak for all sects of Christianity, but the evangelical south is all about saving face. The southern Christian will flat out deny any sort of scandal in order to maintain their social standing to the point of letting whatever that “scandal” may be ruin everything around them. They’ll participate in mental Olympics the likes of which could ensnare the cleverest minds by why of justifying something they know damn well to be morally wrong with some tenuous reference to their little holy book of vast interpretation.</p>

<p>Having conversations about humanity and conservation with these staunch <em>Believer</em> types often engenders frustration. Many of my conversations with family (and some friends) of the Christian ilk ultimately devolves to their dismissal of “matters of this world” for the reason that their life is not here, but “<em>with Jesus</em>.” Which is to say, we don’t care about anyone’s tomorrow “<em>here</em>” because our tomorrow is “<em>there</em>.”</p>

<p>So, basically, fuck us.</p>

<p>Spelling it out this way to a Christian will certainly send them into a fit of “why I nevers” as they clutch their pearls and back pedal in attempt to clarify their position. But the fact of the matter remains that most of these folks, again not bad people per se, live disconnected from this life experience because they believe in the promise of life ever after in some sort of heaven.</p>

<p>That core value is poison.</p>

<p>On the surface it may not <em>look</em> bad. Hell, heaven may even sound like a nice place to some, though I argue the notion of lying at the feet of a space tyrant whose kingdom is lined with streets of gold sounds far too much like a Capitalist hell to me, but to each their own. The poison, though, is that ultimately this belief exonerates the believer from any sense of responsibility of ownership on this planet; it’s temporary. Sabastian Junger in his book <em>Tribe: On Homecoming and Belonging</em> attributes littering (and fraudulent government assistance) to a lack of concern for one’s community to a <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/7685121-in-this-sense-littering-is-an-exceedingly-petty-version-of">feeling or sense of not belonging, of not having ownership</a>.</p>

<p>So, the belief that one is “<em>not of this world</em>” absolves one of ownership in matters this world. <em>And it fucking shows</em>.</p>

<p>It is unanimously the Republican Right that marches industry across land and home, raping earth and family and leaving utter devastation in its wake. Oh, and guess who foots the bill of repairing all that strip-mined land and poisoned water? The tax payer; or: the fucking poor to be exact.</p>

<p>How anyone with any moral compass can turn a blind eye to this is beyond me. How anyone can look at what Industry has left in its wake in places like West Virginia or western Kentucky, how the land and people have been reduced to husks, how this is happening now in Alaska, how it’s actively in planning stages to happen in our national forests, how anyone can acknowledge that morally bankrupt dismissal of humanity and nature, and wave it away with some pissant piety like “<em>I just have to let go and let God</em>” is utter fucking insanity to me.</p>

<p>And yet that very <em>utter fucking insanity</em> appears to account for about half of our voting populace. So, as the poison of evangelical ideology continues to creep itself into American politics, laws, and legislation, we see more and more of this mistreatment of human life—and natural wildlife—transpire with indifference, if not utter contempt, for both.</p>

<p>We watched the Patagonia film <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OGjnIG7puzY"><em>Public Trust</em></a> last night, which is what stewed this sleeping rage inside of me. In that film, which I highly recommend, you’ll see that the current modus operandi of the <em>Right</em>, via financial motivations of <em>Big Industry</em>, is to evangelize and politicize the renouncement of our Public Lands. With the promise of “trillions of dollars” and euphemisms like “energy independence,” the plan of these evil fucks is to rescind federal ownership of Public Lands and turn them over to the states, which ultimately means, the lands—or at the very least the mineral rights—will be sold post-haste to private companies whereupon they will be turned into dystopian oil mines, stripped completely of life and beauty and left for bare. Left for the growing lower class to foot the bill of repair.</p>

<p>But, hey…some folks get to go be with Jesus, so really who gives a fuck, right?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
