<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>deviljames.com</title>
   
   <link>https://deviljames.com</link>
   <description>A blog.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Divided States of Absurdity</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//utter-shitshow</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//utter-shitshow</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“The government itself, which is only the mode which the people have chosen to execute their will, is equally liable to be abused and perverted before the people can act through it.”
— Henry David Thoreau; <em>Civil Disobedience</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Welp.</p>

<p>Did we really expect any different from this election?</p>

<p>I certainly didn’t. And yet, I’m still dismayed.</p>

<p>This country and this government are a duet performing an utter shit show for the world to gasp—or laugh—at.</p>

<p>But this isn’t a joke.</p>

<p>America is seeing itself divided in the worst possible way. This division isn’t a division of party. This is a division of humanity. Goddamn near half of this country stands in favor of a party—and a man—that support and stir racism, misogyny, and growing socioeconomic class division. Stand in favor of is too light a phrase…they fucking champion this shit.</p>

<p>And the rest of us? We are utterly flummoxed.</p>

<p>This trend of a divided country does not support healthy growth of any kind. And, it cannot stand.</p>

<p>Because as it stands, we are stuck.</p>

<p>It’s frustrating to see this unfold and it’s absolutely soul-crushing to feel powerless against what looks and feels like the de-evolution of our country, counties, cities, towns, communities, and even families.</p>

<p>But. Giving up isn’t an option. Vigilance is necessary.</p>

<p>I don’t care where anyone stands or who they “like,” evil interests are working against all of our best interests. We need now, more than ever, to figure out how to get on the same page with each other. I don’t have the <em>how’s</em>, nor do I have any real answers. I just know it’s imperative we don’t let these crony fucks destroy us in the process of destroying our country.</p>

<p>And, if you’re out there seeing these numbers rolling in and you’re feeling increasingly marginalized or scared or under-valued, please know that’s not true. You are important. You matter. And your are needed.</p>

<p>Stay safe out there.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
