<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>deviljames.com</title>
   
   <link>https://deviljames.com</link>
   <description>A blog.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>That Whole Hillbilly Elegy Thing</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//hillbilly-elegy</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//hillbilly-elegy</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>For those of us that knew it was coming, yesterday it came: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KW_3aaoSOYg">Netflix released their trailer for <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em></a>. And, it looks a bit more atrocious than I expected.</p>

<p>For those not in the know, you’re probably seeing this all over your social media feed and wondering what the hell for. <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em> came to life first as a memoir by one <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._D._Vance">J.D. Vance</a>, where it spent an absurd amount of time on the New York Times Top Ten list. The book hit shelves at a crucial time: after the election of Donald Trump as president.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/elegyBook.jpg" alt="Hillbilly Elegy by J.D. Vance" /></p>

<p>Perhaps that was by design. For if this book had just been a memoir about one guy’s experience growing up poor and white, with some honestly entertaining anecdotes about his grandmother—<em>Mawmaw</em>—then perhaps it would have done just fine, and most likely we wouldn’t be having these ongoing conversations about it four years later. There likely wouldn’t be a film directed by Oscar winning filmmaker, Ron Howard, and starring Oscar darlings, Glenn Close and Amy Adams.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/elegyMovie.jpg" alt="Glenn Close and Amy Adams in _Hillbilly Elegy_" /></p>

<p>Yet here we are still talking about it, four years later. We’re talking about it so much so that folks are damn near making a living by doing so. Many books and essays have been written in response. And there’s an incredibly fun and insightful podcast, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/user-972848621-463073718">The Trillbilly Worker’s Party</a>, that got its start by critically responding to the book.</p>

<p>So, what is it about <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em> that’s got us all in a stir?</p>

<p>There’s a lot wrong with this book. I’ll start with: instead of being one man’s memoir about one man’s experience, Vance positions his book as “<em>A Memoir of a Family and Culture in Crisis</em>.” Instead of <em>his</em> experience and <em>his</em> family’s struggles and reasons for <em>their</em> beliefs and <em>their</em> handlings of <em>their</em> goings-on, he makes wide assertions about the <em>whole</em>  of Appalachia. It’s not J.D. Vance’s experience, it’s the Appalachian experience.</p>

<p>And it’s that assertion as fact that has led to this book becoming the “answer” to the question so many people were—and still are—asking; how the fuck did Donald Trump get elected as president?</p>

<p>The real problem is: J.D. Vance’s singular experience is absolutely not the shared experience of Appalachia. No one’s singular experience is ever that.</p>

<p>Furthermore is the assumption that Appalachia is composed entirely of poor white working-class folk. It’s not. Appalachia is exceptionally well-diversified.</p>

<p>And then there’s the question: what, and where,is Appalachia?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This is where I diverge from much of the critical commentary. Yes, absolutely, the Appalachian Mountains are a vast range that extends north to south across many states and even into Canada. But, let’s be honest here, no one in New York state refers to themselves as Appalachian. We all know what region we are speaking of. And, even in parceling out that area for discourse, those hills and hollers of Eastern Kentucky, Tennessee, Western North Carolina, Virginia, the whole of West Virginia, and pieces of Pennsylvania, even then we still maintain a cornucopia of diversity. The hemming and hawing over how much ground and how many people the Appalachian Mountains encompass in the general discourse of what’s ultimately wrong about these generalized and white-washed perspectives on this region is a bit tired and lazy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Within this region, Vance makes sweeping assertions about family, faith, politics, desires, motivations, and so much more. Be it by design or by ignorance, Vance furthers the negatives of White appropriation by disassociating the collective culture and voice of the many for that of his own.</p>

<p>Perhaps most disturbing is that Vance essentially victim-blames the region for their plight. It’s their fault for not seeking higher education. It’s their fault for not seeking to better themselves. It’s their fault that meth and opioids have swept the hills and hollers in staggering numbers in comparison to other parts of this country. Certainly crony Capitalism, in its avarice and machinanations, sweeping those hilltops for decades, stripping the land of resource, poisoning the waters and earth with its detritus, working its men and women to the bone, and when the resources are all gone, gathering up their companies and jobs, and up and leaving the people behind, tired, unemployed, and in pain with little to hold in their hands but the fucking bill had absolutely nothing to do with the plight of Appalachia.</p>

<p>But mostly, it’s their fault for not leaving.</p>

<p>But, then again, Vance is now a Yale graduate and Venture Capitalist who’s left his home behind in his attempts to further Capitalism, while seemingly doing little beyond shake a finger at his home and call it out for being lazy and backwards. So, why would we expect his opinion to be any different? He’s living Ayn Rand’s dream.</p>

<p>The problem with the book is that people read the book and they think, “ah, ok, this is how <em>poor white trash</em> think and operate,” and they build or bolster prejudice toward an entire region based upon that. People look at Appalachia and think it’s beyond help. Its people are stubborn and stupid and reaping what they’ve sown. And while certainly people like Vance’s family exist in that region—they exist in all regions—those people don’t compose that region. And thusly the entire region suffers further.</p>

<p>The people of Appalachia deserve better. They’re not a people to be gawked at via poverty porn vehicles like <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, or to be judged from the perspectives of one man. No person or regian deserves that.</p>

<p>Certainly there is crisis in Appalachia, but it’s not the crisis of lazy indignation. It’s the crisis of Industry having raped and pillaged the land and people to the point of exhaustion. The plight of Appalachia isn’t the byproduct of ignorant, lazy, drug-addicted and well-fare trickstery denizens. The plight of Appalachia is Capitalism. And in that regard Appalachia is no different than Detroit.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about the realities of Appalachia, there’s far better options than <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>. Here’s a few:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/user-972848621-463073718">Trilbilly Worker’s Party Podcast</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/what-you-are-getting-wrong-about-appalachia-none/9780998904146">What You are Getting Wrong About Appalachia</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/appalachian-reckoning-a-region-responds-to-hillbilly-elegy/9781946684790?aid=185&amp;listref=appalachia-as-depicted-by-appalachians">Appalachian Reckoning</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bittersoutherner.com/hillbillies-need-no-elegy-appalachian-reckoning">The Bitter Southerner</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074605/?ref_=fn_al_tt_2">Harlan County, USA</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Or, <em>and this may be a stretch</em>, but go visit this region. Go hike its mountains. Visit its towns. Talk to its people. Spend a few dollars there. We can learn a lot about things online, but I’m still a sucker for good ol’ life experience.</p>

<p>As for <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, the film, while its trailer smacks of poverty porn, I’m hoping that it takes a more singular view. I’m hoping the notion of one man speaking for many is removed from the film and we just get the story of a family and their trials and triumphs as they may be. But, we’ll just have to wait and see on that.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, if you’re going to support something Appalachian, let it be anything but <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, please.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A Tale of Two Cronenbergs</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//cronenbergs</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//cronenbergs</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Everybody’s a mad scientist, and life is their lab.”<br />
— David Cronenberg</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As I’ve previously mentioned, we’re running through a marathon of sixty-one horror movies that we started on September 1st. (that <a href="https://letterboxd.com/writeknuckled/list/2020s-61-days-of-horror/">list is here</a>.) We just recently completed the little section I affectionately refer to as <em>The Mind Fuck Films</em>: <em>Scanners</em>, <em>The Fury</em>, <em>Possessor</em>, and <em>Pontypool</em>.</p>

<p>I had seen <em>Scanners</em> (multiple times) and <em>Pontypool</em> before, but the other two were new to me, and <em>Possessor</em> is new to all of us as it was released only this year. I was excited to add it in there along with <em>Scanners</em> for obvious reasons; like father like son.</p>

<p>I have devoured most—if not all—of David Cronenberg’s films, to which I would normally refer to as simply <em>Cronenberg</em> films; however, with <em>Possessor</em>, Brandon Cronenberg has more than made himself a name, to which I believe going forward, we will have to clarify <em>which</em> Cronenberg we are referring to.</p>

<p><em>Possessor</em> is beyond psychological, it’s a neurological gore-fest thriller wrapped up in a frame signifying it to be a work of fine art. It is beautifully crafted in every capacity. Andrea Riseborough (<em>Mandy</em>) and Christopher Abbot (<em>It Comes at Night</em>) take lead in the film and both provide astounding performances. Karim Hussain’s photography is stunning. And, Matthew Hannam slices like an iron chef. Literally, no one slouches on this film.</p>

<p>I’ve not seen Brandon’s previous film, <em>Antiviral</em>, but I plan to rectify that immediately. I’m bewildered by the eight years that stand between that film and <em>Possessor</em>, and only hope that this indicates Brandon’s commitment to craft being what kept him away from producing another film. If it’s not clear, I am hungry for more from Brandon Cronenberg.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, I can’t help but imagine—fantasize—about what it must’ve been like to grow up under the wing of David Cronenberg. To live in under the house rules of a man whose cinematic work is undoubtedly some of the most creative and interesting of the last several decades. What was that like? How did that influence—which it obviously has—Brandon? And how did it potentially encumber him?</p>

<p>I look at other brilliant creative, cinematic minds like my personal favorite, David Lynch, and his daughter, Jennifer Lynch, who has certainly made a career for herself, but has as of yet failed to make a <em>name</em> for herself. Her film, <em>Surveillance</em>, bless its heart, bless <em>her</em> heart, was an utter travesty. And so I wonder, what was the dynamic of the Cronenberg home which beget another profound voice in Brandon, where the Lynch home seems to have failed to pass on that unique gene?</p>

<p>Perhaps it’s gross of me to ponder such things. Perhaps it’s gross to even assume the child of a genius to even <em>want</em> to follow in the path of creativity.</p>

<p>And, yet, it seems so often they do.</p>

<p>That said, <em>Possessor</em> is an absolute <strong>banger</strong>. This is a must-see. And I cannot wait for it to get a proper release. Already pre-ordered on iTunes.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>It's Spooky Season</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//spooky-time</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//spooky-time</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Eye of newt, and toe of frog,<br />
Wool of bat, and tongue of dog,<br />
Adder’s fork, and blind-worm’s sting,<br />
Lizard’s leg, and owlet’s wing,—<br />
For a charm of powerful trouble,<br />
Like a hell-broth boil and bubble.<br />
Double, double toil and trouble;<br />
Fire burn, and caldron bubble.”<br />
― William Shakespeare</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let’s keep this one light.</p>

<p>It’s October 1st.</p>

<p>It’s that most glorious time of the year. When the strangling tendrils of summer’s humidity slink away and in their place the air takes on a crisp bite. When the smells shift to cider and pumpkin. And the leaves shift from greens to hues of orange and red. I can finally wear jeans and hoodies again. (Y’all, it’s fucking hot in the south. And it’s <em>not</em> a dry heat.)</p>

<p>But, most important of all this means it’s time for the mosquitoes to hibernate, or better yet, <strong>DIE</strong>!</p>

<p>Ok, seriously, most importantly it means it’s finally <strong>HALLOWEEN</strong> season!!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="assets/images/halloweenMe.jpg" alt="What the hell even am I?" /></p>

  <p>What the hell even am I? <em><strong>Why</strong></em> do I have the stigmata?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Whatever <em>normal</em> is, I’ve never been that. <em>Obviously</em>. Just look at that picture up there of me a kid. The others? All smiling faces and radiant colors. Me? Some blasphemous scourge shrouded in black all ready to devour little souls—and lots of candy. <em>Honestly</em>, why do I have the stigmata? I need to talk to my mother about this.</p>

<p>If it’s not clear by the provided photographic childhood evidence, I’ve always been obsessed with the spooky and macabre. And I got it honest. My mom would hand down the latest Stephen King novels once she finished reading them. My grandfather would let me sit in on horror and gore movies I was <em>way</em> too young to see.</p>

<p>But a favorite story my mother tells to back this up is of a night she went out and left me with my grandparents. She came home, late, after midnight-ish, and she says the house was dark and quiet save for the TV glowing in the living room. When she walked in, she found me there, wide-eyed, glued to a black-and-white vampire movie while my grandfather snored beside me.</p>

<p>That obsession continues.</p>

<p>I can’t think of a time in my childhood or adolescence that I wasn’t nose deep in a Stephen King (or, yes, Dean Koontz) novel or shoveling popcorn into my mouth while watching the latest—and often, least greatest—horror film. In adulthood, the search for all things horror is at a constant fever pitch. When it comes to horror in film and literature I consider myself a connoisseur. Though, scary fucking weirdo may also be accurate.</p>

<p>For this Halloween season, our first under pandemic conditions, no haunted houses or mazes, or double features at the cinema, I decided to craft us up an at home sixty-one day horror movie marathon. If you’re interested, you can check out the list of films over on my <a href="https://letterboxd.com/writeknuckled/list/2020s-61-days-of-horror/">Letterboxd account</a>, and while you’d be 30 days late to this party, feel free to join in and follow along.</p>

<p>Most of these films I’ve seen before, but I’ve made certain to add some newer and/or unseen classic films to the list. The beautiful thing about this marathon is that my significant other also loves Halloween and “<em>spoopy</em>” things, but she’s not seen even a fraction of the horror canon I have. And one of my favorite things is sharing something I love with someone I love.</p>

<p>I’ve tried to maintain a thread through the films, linking them together in ways that make sense, even if not immediately obvious. One glaring exception is that our first film, <em>An American Werewolf in London</em> is a film we watched out of a bit of “necessity,” meaning it kept popping up in some documentaries we were watching and she continued to comment on it. So, it simply had to be our fist film. From there, we get some of the classic goodies, some zombies, more werewolves, eldrich monsters, aliens, creatures, and witches…and so on.</p>

<p>The first film on the list that will be completely new to me, is quite new to all of us, and that’s <em>Antebellum</em>. I’ve not seen it yet, and while I’ve also not read the book <em>Kindred</em> by Octavia Butler, I’m dumfounded that her name is not listed in the credits. How is this film <em>not</em> based on that book? I guess I’ll have to see the film and read the book and make that assessment for myself.</p>

<p>We’re still trying to find other ways to make up for the lack of overall Halloween-ness this season. I’d love to find some fun socially-distanced things to do with friends and family. Meanwhile, our list of horror movies and decorations are doing well to keep us spirited this season.</p>

<p>But honestly, this is just kind of our normal aesthetic.</p>

<p>It’s always Halloween here.
<img src="assets/images/pumpkin.jpg" alt="John Carpenter's _Halloween_" /></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Poor Little Hysterical Witch!</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//haxan</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//haxan</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“To me, a witch is a woman that is capable of letting her intuition take hold of her actions, that communes with her environment, that isn’t afraid of facing challenges.”<br />
Paulo Coelho</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I promise myself—because no one else reads this—that I won’t spend every post lambasting religion. But, again, watched a film last night that set me to seething about its subject matter, of which religion is a prime focus.</p>

<p>That film: <em>Häxan: Witchcraft Through the Ages</em>.</p>

<p><em>Häxan</em> is a 1922 documentary/fantasy film directed by Benjamin Christensen that seeks to educate us on the history and plight of the Witch, from the dawn of time up until the then modern years.</p>

<p><em>Häxan</em> has long been a part of the esteemed <a href="https://criterion.com">Criterion Collection</a>, and is painstakingly restored via an impressive 2K restoration process and presented on Blu Ray with a handful of features.</p>

<p>This to say, it’s a film considered by many to be valuable in the cinematic canon. However, as the film settled into itself—and it’s not until part two that actual actor performances begin—I often found myself laughing <em>at</em> the film. Quite mockingly in fact. It feels campy, and the subject matter being quite far removed from our current time struck me as rather goofy. That was until I remembered: <em>holy shit, this is a documentary</em>. This isn’t meant to be comical farce. This is meant to explore the history and reality of the witch and her plight.</p>

<p>It was then that the severity of what we were watching set in. This is exposing centuries of barbaric mistreatment and misogyny toward women, predominantly at the behest of the Church.</p>

<p>For a woman to be labeled, tried, condemned and executed as a witch required scarcely anything beyond her being, say, old and ugly, or perhaps young and pretty—leaving a completely subjective and hazy line for any female to toe. All it took was someone’s accusation.</p>

<p>If merely called a witch, a woman was removed from her home and essentially tortured to the point of either admitting to things she’s never done just to stop the barbarism, or for the few strong of will, being punished for their refusal to confess.</p>

<p>Being accused—quite frankly by any fucking person in town—of witchcraft was a death sentence. The only question being how long and how painful the remaining moments of her life would be.</p>

<p>The implements of torture of the day were seemingly endless. Which brings me to wonder, who the fuck sits around and comes up with these methods and devices of torture. Apparently frightened, entitled men of “<em>faith</em>.”</p>

<p>In one scene in the film, Christensen uses artwork of the period and title cards to demonstrate one method of torture in which a woman would be bound at her hands and feet, like a cowboy might tie a hog, and then thrown into whatever body of water was nearby. Priests with long oars would ensure the woman remained face down. If she were to die and sink, meaning she was not a witch, the priests would praise their god for her soul having been saved. If she refused to sink, meaning obviously she’s a witch, she would be removed and burned at the stake.</p>

<p>In another scene, this time with performers, Christensen takes us on a tour of what it might look like, from start to finish, for a woman to be declared a witch and thusly dealt with. In this scene, a young woman’s husband has fallen ill. We learn that he had grown dizzy, and the most logical of conclusions for this malady was that the poor man was cursed by a witch—certainly it couldn’t have been that he worked hard in the midday sun and failed to hydrate. Or, happened to catch whatever fucking other myriad sickness of that day that essentially ate life away from millions.</p>

<p>Nope. Had to be a witch.</p>

<p>As <em>Fate</em> would have it a poor and elderly woman comes to their home and asks for something to eat. The young lady provides food, but is perturbed by the old woman’s wrinkles and deep set eyes. Certainly this is her witch. Long and short, church men take her away and torture her to the point of confession and dispatch of her as well as all the other women she was forced to name. Irony of ironies, the young woman who set this all in motion…she was named a witch by the old lady and she as well was dispatched accordingly.</p>

<p>What I find compelling about his film is how it illustrates a subject I’ve long been drawn to, that being what I refer to as the <em>Fear and Myth of the <strong>Other</strong></em>. Be that <em>Other</em> race, gender, creed, sexuality geography, age, etc. those unlike us become ever so easily subjected to our prejudices, and as this film explores, have for centuries upon centuries now.</p>

<p>Perhaps the fear of <em>Otherness</em> is simply an inherent human trait. I personally don’t like that idea at all. I find life far more flavorful and exciting because there are so many <em>not</em> like me. How and why so many are scared of different cultures and ideas is beyond me, and also grossly fascinates me.</p>

<p>Theistic religions are at their core an exclusive ideology. You’re either of their ilk, or you’re not; you’re an infidel. Most of these religions seek to allay that <em>Otherness</em> via proselytizing; through <em>conversion</em>.  But make no mistake, if the <em>Other</em> does not become like them, they’re useless to them. (Again, even I admit that I know many religious folk—be they Christian, Muslim, etc—that aren’t awful, racist, sexist, homophobic, misogynistic people…but they’re exceptions to the rule.)</p>

<p>Ultimately with the benefit of decades of hindsight, we learn that what men and women of the times of the Middle Ages called a witch was often no more than a widower or a young woman who’d not found a husband, or sadly, perhaps a woman born with a mental or physical malady. The true crime? These women were not only shunned by their community, but destroyed by it.</p>

<p>Here we are in the Common Era year of 2020, and while we may not drag women from their homes to test their buoyancy before burning them at the stake, we still don’t universally treat them as equals. Women are still blamed for their own assaults, be those random or domestic partnerships. If not blamed, certainly they are held to bear the burden of proof. Women are still assumed to be the homemaker and the caretaker. They’re still expected to leave their pursuits and desires behind to nurture their family; whereas, a man should be just as willing and capable.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/haxan2.jpg" alt="That tonguey devil..." /></p>

<p>As Coelho alludes above, the witches of our day aren’t covered in ointment and licking the asshole of the devil in a cemetery any more than they were in the days of the Salem trials. Witches then and now are simply women with more desire in their heart for their own growth and strength than that of subservience and the fortitude to pursue anything otherwise.</p>

<p>And it’s only feeble little men—commonly shrouded in “<em>the cloth</em>“—that are frightened by that notion.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Poor little hysterical witch! In the middle ages you were in conflict with the church. Now it is with the law.”<br />
— <em>Häxan</em></p>
</blockquote>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Staying Sane in Isolation</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//isolation</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//isolation</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“<em>Doldrums. Doldrums. Eviler than the Devil. Boredom makes men to villains…</em>”<br />
<strong>Thomas Wake</strong> (Willem Dafoe); <em>The Lighthouse (2019 dir. Robert Eggers)</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>We’re having a little <em>61 Days of Horror</em> horror movie marathon at the house. I’ve worked to curate a list of films and group them together in some sort sensible fashion. Prior to last night’s film we watched the Universal Classic <em>The Creature from the Black Lagoon</em>. I decided a nice tie-in to that film—which would also thread us toward a series of <em>witch</em> films—would be Robbert Eggers’ <em>The Lighthouse</em>.</p>

<p>This was my second viewing of the film. Typically any first viewing is purely for enjoyment’s sake. <em>The Lighthouse</em> is one of those films that sort of takes up residence with you. Sets up in the grey matter and makes itself at home. This second viewing, I sat dumfounded as the ending credits burned across the screen.</p>

<p>I’m not going to review the film. I will encourage you to watch it. But, considering the fact that we’re still in a bit of a quarantine state, I wanted to explore the themes of the film. Primarily that of isolation and madness.</p>

<p>Humans are a social creature. We’re meant to gather and interact. To celebrate, as well as test, each other. Throughout time, it’s primarily those pushed to the fringes of a society that snap. Our relationship with community has been under attack for years, decades even. A people divided is much weaker than a people united. One thing is certain about the 2020 Pandemic, it has foisted isolation upon all of us.</p>

<p>Sadly, most folk are prepared for sitting alone with their thoughts.</p>

<p>As you watch <em>The Lighthoues</em>, you see how isolation works. How it comes on slow like and makes itself a friend; peppers you with little kisses. How those kisses transition to suckling, and how before you even realize it, it’s plum gnawing away at your sanity. The person you were, the ideologies and convictions you held, hell, even your hygiene and personal aesthetics are changed to the point of being unrecognizable.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/lighthouse_water.jpeg" alt="Robert Pattinson in The Lighthouse" /></p>

<p><em>The Lighthouse</em> masterfully explores this theme. I’m reminded of <strong>Roman Polanski</strong>’s <em>Repulsion</em>. It’s far easier to observe the machinations of isolation in something like a 100 minutes long film. It’s far more difficult to observe them in the day-to-day. And in this day and age—especially during a pandemic-induced quarantine—vigilance of self and sanity should be priority number one.</p>

<p>One must strive to gain sentry over one’s self. Certainly a sound practice against isolation madness is not allowing for ourselves to fall into personal echo chambers or poisonous <em>group-thought</em>. Another is a bit more of a life journey. One of coming to appreciate stillness; quiet, alone. Strengthening the mind against itself.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
