<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>deviljames.com</title>
   
   <link>https://deviljames.com</link>
   <description>A blog.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Working Through Weakness</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//working-through-weakness</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//working-through-weakness</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“You’ve never lived what you are thinking, and that isn’t good. Only the ideas we actually live are of any value.”<br />
— Hermann Hesse <em>Demian</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>2020 has been a strange year. Pretty much for all of us, I’d say. It’s been a year that pushed most of us to live primarily indoors. It forced many of us into a more sedentary lifestyle. It took away from us things—and access to things—we took for granted.</p>

<p>Things like the gym.</p>

<p>Now, if I’m being fair, I’d slacked off from the gym well before COVID-19 took it away from me.</p>

<p>Not going into the details, but our little world was thrown a bit upside down in early 2019. The events of that time led to a similar reclusion. Once the normalcy of that settled in, excuses weaseled their way in, and before you know it excuses brought their lousy son of a bitch friend, the enemy of health and productivity: Weakness.</p>

<p>Before long my evenings consisted of soft clothes and receding into the couch for hours with a tub of popcorn and a six-pack of beer.</p>

<p>That frivolously wasteful use of precious time perpetuated until I’d had enough…and then COVID hit.</p>

<p>That said, today marked the end of that bullshit.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Divided States of Absurdity</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//utter-shitshow</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//utter-shitshow</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“The government itself, which is only the mode which the people have chosen to execute their will, is equally liable to be abused and perverted before the people can act through it.”
— Henry David Thoreau; <em>Civil Disobedience</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Welp.</p>

<p>Did we really expect any different from this election?</p>

<p>I certainly didn’t. And yet, I’m still dismayed.</p>

<p>This country and this government are a duet performing an utter shit show for the world to gasp—or laugh—at.</p>

<p>But this isn’t a joke.</p>

<p>America is seeing itself divided in the worst possible way. This division isn’t a division of party. This is a division of humanity. Goddamn near half of this country stands in favor of a party—and a man—that support and stir racism, misogyny, and growing socioeconomic class division. Stand in favor of is too light a phrase…they fucking champion this shit.</p>

<p>And the rest of us? We are utterly flummoxed.</p>

<p>This trend of a divided country does not support healthy growth of any kind. And, it cannot stand.</p>

<p>Because as it stands, we are stuck.</p>

<p>It’s frustrating to see this unfold and it’s absolutely soul-crushing to feel powerless against what looks and feels like the de-evolution of our country, counties, cities, towns, communities, and even families.</p>

<p>But. Giving up isn’t an option. Vigilance is necessary.</p>

<p>I don’t care where anyone stands or who they “like,” evil interests are working against all of our best interests. We need now, more than ever, to figure out how to get on the same page with each other. I don’t have the <em>how’s</em>, nor do I have any real answers. I just know it’s imperative we don’t let these crony fucks destroy us in the process of destroying our country.</p>

<p>And, if you’re out there seeing these numbers rolling in and you’re feeling increasingly marginalized or scared or under-valued, please know that’s not true. You are important. You matter. And your are needed.</p>

<p>Stay safe out there.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>That Whole Hillbilly Elegy Thing</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//hillbilly-elegy</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//hillbilly-elegy</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>For those of us that knew it was coming, yesterday it came: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KW_3aaoSOYg">Netflix released their trailer for <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em></a>. And, it looks a bit more atrocious than I expected.</p>

<p>For those not in the know, you’re probably seeing this all over your social media feed and wondering what the hell for. <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em> came to life first as a memoir by one <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._D._Vance">J.D. Vance</a>, where it spent an absurd amount of time on the New York Times Top Ten list. The book hit shelves at a crucial time: after the election of Donald Trump as president.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/elegyBook.jpg" alt="Hillbilly Elegy by J.D. Vance" /></p>

<p>Perhaps that was by design. For if this book had just been a memoir about one guy’s experience growing up poor and white, with some honestly entertaining anecdotes about his grandmother—<em>Mawmaw</em>—then perhaps it would have done just fine, and most likely we wouldn’t be having these ongoing conversations about it four years later. There likely wouldn’t be a film directed by Oscar winning filmmaker, Ron Howard, and starring Oscar darlings, Glenn Close and Amy Adams.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/elegyMovie.jpg" alt="Glenn Close and Amy Adams in _Hillbilly Elegy_" /></p>

<p>Yet here we are still talking about it, four years later. We’re talking about it so much so that folks are damn near making a living by doing so. Many books and essays have been written in response. And there’s an incredibly fun and insightful podcast, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/user-972848621-463073718">The Trillbilly Worker’s Party</a>, that got its start by critically responding to the book.</p>

<p>So, what is it about <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em> that’s got us all in a stir?</p>

<p>There’s a lot wrong with this book. I’ll start with: instead of being one man’s memoir about one man’s experience, Vance positions his book as “<em>A Memoir of a Family and Culture in Crisis</em>.” Instead of <em>his</em> experience and <em>his</em> family’s struggles and reasons for <em>their</em> beliefs and <em>their</em> handlings of <em>their</em> goings-on, he makes wide assertions about the <em>whole</em>  of Appalachia. It’s not J.D. Vance’s experience, it’s the Appalachian experience.</p>

<p>And it’s that assertion as fact that has led to this book becoming the “answer” to the question so many people were—and still are—asking; how the fuck did Donald Trump get elected as president?</p>

<p>The real problem is: J.D. Vance’s singular experience is absolutely not the shared experience of Appalachia. No one’s singular experience is ever that.</p>

<p>Furthermore is the assumption that Appalachia is composed entirely of poor white working-class folk. It’s not. Appalachia is exceptionally well-diversified.</p>

<p>And then there’s the question: what, and where,is Appalachia?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This is where I diverge from much of the critical commentary. Yes, absolutely, the Appalachian Mountains are a vast range that extends north to south across many states and even into Canada. But, let’s be honest here, no one in New York state refers to themselves as Appalachian. We all know what region we are speaking of. And, even in parceling out that area for discourse, those hills and hollers of Eastern Kentucky, Tennessee, Western North Carolina, Virginia, the whole of West Virginia, and pieces of Pennsylvania, even then we still maintain a cornucopia of diversity. The hemming and hawing over how much ground and how many people the Appalachian Mountains encompass in the general discourse of what’s ultimately wrong about these generalized and white-washed perspectives on this region is a bit tired and lazy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Within this region, Vance makes sweeping assertions about family, faith, politics, desires, motivations, and so much more. Be it by design or by ignorance, Vance furthers the negatives of White appropriation by disassociating the collective culture and voice of the many for that of his own.</p>

<p>Perhaps most disturbing is that Vance essentially victim-blames the region for their plight. It’s their fault for not seeking higher education. It’s their fault for not seeking to better themselves. It’s their fault that meth and opioids have swept the hills and hollers in staggering numbers in comparison to other parts of this country. Certainly crony Capitalism, in its avarice and machinanations, sweeping those hilltops for decades, stripping the land of resource, poisoning the waters and earth with its detritus, working its men and women to the bone, and when the resources are all gone, gathering up their companies and jobs, and up and leaving the people behind, tired, unemployed, and in pain with little to hold in their hands but the fucking bill had absolutely nothing to do with the plight of Appalachia.</p>

<p>But mostly, it’s their fault for not leaving.</p>

<p>But, then again, Vance is now a Yale graduate and Venture Capitalist who’s left his home behind in his attempts to further Capitalism, while seemingly doing little beyond shake a finger at his home and call it out for being lazy and backwards. So, why would we expect his opinion to be any different? He’s living Ayn Rand’s dream.</p>

<p>The problem with the book is that people read the book and they think, “ah, ok, this is how <em>poor white trash</em> think and operate,” and they build or bolster prejudice toward an entire region based upon that. People look at Appalachia and think it’s beyond help. Its people are stubborn and stupid and reaping what they’ve sown. And while certainly people like Vance’s family exist in that region—they exist in all regions—those people don’t compose that region. And thusly the entire region suffers further.</p>

<p>The people of Appalachia deserve better. They’re not a people to be gawked at via poverty porn vehicles like <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, or to be judged from the perspectives of one man. No person or regian deserves that.</p>

<p>Certainly there is crisis in Appalachia, but it’s not the crisis of lazy indignation. It’s the crisis of Industry having raped and pillaged the land and people to the point of exhaustion. The plight of Appalachia isn’t the byproduct of ignorant, lazy, drug-addicted and well-fare trickstery denizens. The plight of Appalachia is Capitalism. And in that regard Appalachia is no different than Detroit.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about the realities of Appalachia, there’s far better options than <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>. Here’s a few:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/user-972848621-463073718">Trilbilly Worker’s Party Podcast</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/what-you-are-getting-wrong-about-appalachia-none/9780998904146">What You are Getting Wrong About Appalachia</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/appalachian-reckoning-a-region-responds-to-hillbilly-elegy/9781946684790?aid=185&amp;listref=appalachia-as-depicted-by-appalachians">Appalachian Reckoning</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bittersoutherner.com/hillbillies-need-no-elegy-appalachian-reckoning">The Bitter Southerner</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074605/?ref_=fn_al_tt_2">Harlan County, USA</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Or, <em>and this may be a stretch</em>, but go visit this region. Go hike its mountains. Visit its towns. Talk to its people. Spend a few dollars there. We can learn a lot about things online, but I’m still a sucker for good ol’ life experience.</p>

<p>As for <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, the film, while its trailer smacks of poverty porn, I’m hoping that it takes a more singular view. I’m hoping the notion of one man speaking for many is removed from the film and we just get the story of a family and their trials and triumphs as they may be. But, we’ll just have to wait and see on that.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, if you’re going to support something Appalachian, let it be anything but <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, please.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>When Bad Movies are Great</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//bad-movies</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//bad-movies</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Other writers, producers, and directors of low-budget films would often put down the film they were making, saying it was just something to make money with. I never felt that. If I took the assignment, I’d give it my best shot.”<br />
— Roger Corman</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I don’t know what makes a <em>bad</em> movie <em>great</em>, but I love a lot of absolutely shitty movies, and I think they’re all amazing.</p>

<p>I grew up watching VHS horror flicks. I was raised on Jason, Freddy, Michael and Leatherface. I saw absolutely every one of their sequels throughout the 80’s and 90’s, as well as their 00’s remakes.  I saw <em>Faces of Death</em> and <em>I Spit on Your Grave</em>. I don’t know why, but I was allowed to see a lot of movies a child should not see.</p>

<p>Many of these films burrowed their mark deep inside my impressionable young mind and remain absolute favorites of mine, to this day, despite being <em>objectively</em> not good movies. One of which I recently sought out on Blu Ray, <em>Slaughterhouse Rock</em>…really bad, but fuck…I love it.</p>

<p>As a kid, and into my teens, I devoured every title in the horror section of my Pick-A-Flick. Eventually the home rental market started to die and gave rise to the whole DVD home ownership market. To say that I embraced this would be an understatement.</p>

<p>I took a long break from the home vide market. But as of late, I’ve fallen right back into stride. In doing so, I don’t find myself seeking out the latest and greatest from the Hollywood machine, I find myself scouring for the best version of those nefarious titles that graced the shelves at my local video stores.</p>

<p>And thankfully due to companies like <a href="https://vinegarsyndrome.com">Vinegar Syndrom</a>, <a href="https://severin-films.com/">Severin Films</a>, <a href="https://www.synapsefilms.com/">Synapse Films</a>, <a href="https://www.codereddvd.com/">Code Red</a>, <a href="http://massacrevideo.com/">Massacre Video</a>, and many others…these otherwise forgotten films are being meticulously revived, restored, and made available to us today.</p>

<p>At this very moment, I’m watching Vinegar Syndrome’s release of the absolutely terrible—and amazing—<em>Spookies</em>, and I can’t help but pine for the days in which these god-awful VHS gems proliferated.</p>

<p>Sure, I love truly <em>fine</em> filmmaking. I love <em>cinema</em>.</p>

<p>But goddamnit, <em>shitty</em> movies forever have a home in my heart. And, I wish more of us loved them.</p>

<p>I want to sit amongst a gathering of many and laugh at the absurdity—and utter bravery—of films like <em>Blood Games</em>, <em>Psychos In Love</em>, <em>Nekromantik</em>, and <em>Body Melt</em>. These movies deserve audiences, are best experienced with others. And yet, without the likes of these daring distribution companies, most of these titles would be utterly lost to us.</p>

<p>I am ever so grateful for the men and women working behind the scenes of these companies, and so many others than I failed to cite—and perhaps, sadly don’t even know exist. You are truly doing the best work in cinema today, you are keeping alive these amazingly terrible movies.</p>

<p>You are doing Lucifer’s work.</p>

<p>And, when COVID finally becomes a shadow in our collective existence, I’ll gather with a few close friends and we’ll watch the <em>Severin Films</em> release of Lucio Fulci’s “<em>The Devil’s Honey</em>”.</p>

<p><a href="https://severin-films.com/shop/the-devils-honey-bluray/"><img src="assets/images/devilHoney.jpg" alt="Lucio Fulci's &quot;The Devil's Honey&quot;" /></a>&gt;</p>

<p>After that, we’ll watch the upcoming 4K UHD release of <em>Dial Code Santa Claus</em> from <em>Vinegar Syndrome</em>.</p>

<p><a href="https://vinegarsyndrome.com/collections/frontpage/products/dial-code-santa-claus"><img src="assets/images/dialSanta.jpg" alt="Dial Code Santa Claus - Vinegar Syndrome" /></a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Driver or Passenger?</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//driver-passenger</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//driver-passenger</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Until you make the unconscious conscious,<br />
it will direct your life<br />
and you will call it fate.”<br />
— Carl Jung</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Aimlessness’s only outcome is entropy.</p>

<p>Opting out of consciously directing our lives does not in turn opt us out of the overall <em>Game of Life</em>. Life continues around us with or without our active participation. No one gets to be an NPC in Life. You’re either directing your thoughts, energy, and actions or someone/thing else is.</p>

<p>Of every tool at our disposal, the mind is by far the most powerful. Unlike other tools, however, the mind is always on and always active. Therefore, we must monitor and maintain our mind and our thoughts. Otherwise, myriad others are working tirelessly to take ownership of your thoughts.</p>

<p>We are being constantly sold things. Every minute of every day. Our minds are under constant attack via advertising, technology, and even our friends. All of which are vying for our time and attention and hoping to rewire our desires and impulses.</p>

<p>It’s a lot easier to see when we are being sold a <em>thing</em>. When the goal of the mental hijacker is to drive us toward a real-world purshase. My better half calls it “<em>being Gramboozled</em>.” We’re flicking our screens all day and seeing these things we don’t have and the creatives behind the ads and the technology understand how to associate these things to reward centers in our minds. Whether we know it or not, we are being programmed to feel like we need these things.</p>

<p>It’s not always just stuff. Nor is it just advertisers. Sometimes the goal is just to keep us in competition, driving each other to appear <em>better than</em>. Sometimes it us. <em>We</em> are actively contributing to the endless <em>FOMO</em> cycle. Think of how most of us curate our online lives to appear as exciting and happy as they possibly can. We share our highlight reels with the world. Meanwhile, we’re looking at each others’ feeds and comparing their highlights, not to our highlights, but to our regular ass, mundane real-world situations.</p>

<p>I’m over here paying bills and developing IBS while ol’ <em>so-and-so</em> is posting pics from the beach; nevermind that we <em>think</em> we saw those same pics last year—beacuse they are from last year. We <em>know</em> that, but we’re allowing our mind to feel left out and less than.</p>

<p>And it’s that kind of thinking that spirals us into <a href="https://deviljames.com/rubbernecking"><em>mental rubbernecking and eventual collisions</em></a>.</p>

<p>We’ve allowed the machinations of someone—person or entity—to guide our thinking. And whomever controls the thought, controls the action.</p>

<p>We have to get into the driver’s seat of our own lives; our own minds.</p>

<p>Otherwise, who knows where we’re headed. But, I can’t imagine it’s where any of us wanted to go.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Magick and Our Thoughts</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//magick-thinking</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//magick-thinking</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“You’re already doing magick — you just don’t know it.”<br />
— Damien Echols</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Rabbits out of hats. Chesty ladies sawed asunder. A card you secretly selected appears in a friend’s purse. These are all examples of parlor magic. Sleight of hand. Simple tricks played on the eye. Or, as <em>Arrested Development</em>’s Gob puts it:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Illusions, Michael. A trick is something a whore does for money…or candy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We’re not talking about that. We’re talking about Magick.</p>

<p>Aleister Crowley is credited with coining the term <em>Magick</em> (magic with a k). And, he did so to differentiate the occult practice, or <em>High Magick</em>, from the said parlor tricks mentioned above. In his religion of <em>Thelema</em>, Crowley defines magick as “the Science and Art of causing Change to occur in conformity with Will.”</p>

<p>In drastically simpler terms, focusing your intention into thoughts that impact your actions, thus affecting change in the world around you.</p>

<p>Many forms of this ideology have made their way into paperbacks, documentaries, LA all-inclusive retreats, and TV talk show circuits. So, let’s not mince words here; there’s plenty of fly-by-night “gurus” looking to take your money. You could lose it on worse things though, but still, don’t get caught up in a cult. Don’t.</p>

<p>As Echols states in our opening quote, “You’re already doing magick…” Our minds are constantly evaluating, processing, conjouring, and ultimately, attracting things into our lives. Ever known someone who’s always complaining about everything? Worse still, are you that person? What if you stopped focusing on what’s going wrong about things and begin to appreciate what’s going right? Or, simply reframe the negative aspects into thoughts about how things can be made better. Even if it’s the simplest of concerns. Even if it’s just that you survived.</p>

<p>Now certainly there’s more to magick than simply thinking positive thoughts. I’m not implying otherwise; volumes upon volumes exist on the subject. But, as Echols points out to us, we are already magicians of our own design whether we know—or accept—it.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/damien.jpeg" alt="Damien Echols" /></p>

<p>If your magickal path goes no further than intentional positive thinking I believe you’ll find your life the better for it.</p>

<p>You may certainly choose to explore further. But start with that.</p>

<p>Make it a habit.</p>

<p>Do it now, think one good intention-soaked thought. See where it takes you.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A Tale of Two Cronenbergs</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//cronenbergs</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//cronenbergs</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Everybody’s a mad scientist, and life is their lab.”<br />
— David Cronenberg</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As I’ve previously mentioned, we’re running through a marathon of sixty-one horror movies that we started on September 1st. (that <a href="https://letterboxd.com/writeknuckled/list/2020s-61-days-of-horror/">list is here</a>.) We just recently completed the little section I affectionately refer to as <em>The Mind Fuck Films</em>: <em>Scanners</em>, <em>The Fury</em>, <em>Possessor</em>, and <em>Pontypool</em>.</p>

<p>I had seen <em>Scanners</em> (multiple times) and <em>Pontypool</em> before, but the other two were new to me, and <em>Possessor</em> is new to all of us as it was released only this year. I was excited to add it in there along with <em>Scanners</em> for obvious reasons; like father like son.</p>

<p>I have devoured most—if not all—of David Cronenberg’s films, to which I would normally refer to as simply <em>Cronenberg</em> films; however, with <em>Possessor</em>, Brandon Cronenberg has more than made himself a name, to which I believe going forward, we will have to clarify <em>which</em> Cronenberg we are referring to.</p>

<p><em>Possessor</em> is beyond psychological, it’s a neurological gore-fest thriller wrapped up in a frame signifying it to be a work of fine art. It is beautifully crafted in every capacity. Andrea Riseborough (<em>Mandy</em>) and Christopher Abbot (<em>It Comes at Night</em>) take lead in the film and both provide astounding performances. Karim Hussain’s photography is stunning. And, Matthew Hannam slices like an iron chef. Literally, no one slouches on this film.</p>

<p>I’ve not seen Brandon’s previous film, <em>Antiviral</em>, but I plan to rectify that immediately. I’m bewildered by the eight years that stand between that film and <em>Possessor</em>, and only hope that this indicates Brandon’s commitment to craft being what kept him away from producing another film. If it’s not clear, I am hungry for more from Brandon Cronenberg.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, I can’t help but imagine—fantasize—about what it must’ve been like to grow up under the wing of David Cronenberg. To live in under the house rules of a man whose cinematic work is undoubtedly some of the most creative and interesting of the last several decades. What was that like? How did that influence—which it obviously has—Brandon? And how did it potentially encumber him?</p>

<p>I look at other brilliant creative, cinematic minds like my personal favorite, David Lynch, and his daughter, Jennifer Lynch, who has certainly made a career for herself, but has as of yet failed to make a <em>name</em> for herself. Her film, <em>Surveillance</em>, bless its heart, bless <em>her</em> heart, was an utter travesty. And so I wonder, what was the dynamic of the Cronenberg home which beget another profound voice in Brandon, where the Lynch home seems to have failed to pass on that unique gene?</p>

<p>Perhaps it’s gross of me to ponder such things. Perhaps it’s gross to even assume the child of a genius to even <em>want</em> to follow in the path of creativity.</p>

<p>And, yet, it seems so often they do.</p>

<p>That said, <em>Possessor</em> is an absolute <strong>banger</strong>. This is a must-see. And I cannot wait for it to get a proper release. Already pre-ordered on iTunes.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Quit Yer Rubbernecking</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//rubbernecking</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//rubbernecking</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Now, water can flow or it can crash. Be water, my friend.”<br />
— Bruce Lee</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Those of us who drive, be it out of necessity or convenience, have most certainly encountered our fair share of traffic jams, or worse, traffic accidents.</p>

<p>Highways are vast networks of concrete and asphalt which allow for a fantastical number of person-carrying vehicles to travel upon. The mind is a lot like a highway system, and our thoughts are a lot like the cars traveling along those neural lanes. The thing about highways is there are a number of “rules of the road” for which anyone operating a vehicle is supposed to abide. We operate as drivers on the road with a certain shared faith in one another that these rules will be observed and we reciprocate by ourselves observing the same rules. Failure on anyone’s part to do so often results in traffic buildup, travel delays, or worse, human fatalities.</p>

<p>These traffic snafus are further exacerbated by fucking rubberneckers.</p>

<p>So, there’s a wreck or a car is pulled over on the side of the road. It seems like an innocent thing, the desire to glance over at what’s going on. Let me just get a peek. Nothing about having seen the wreck will benefit your travels in the least, but you must know, you have to see it. And so does the person behind you, and the person behind them, and the person behind them, and so on and so on, so that three miles back people are gripping their steering wheels in a seething rage because they’re going to be late to work.</p>

<p>The mind is similar.</p>

<p>Our mind generates thoughts at incalculable rates. The mind is like the 405 at peak traffic. (If you’ve driven in Los Angeles, you know what this means. If not, everything you’ve heard about driving in Los Angeles is far more true than you can possibly imagine.) Even concerted effort would fail at trying to chase every thought we produce. The flip side of that is that one doesn’t even have to actively think to find oneself lost in thought.</p>

<p>Obviously not all thoughts are problematic. Many thoughts lead us toward myriad positive results. We think about and solve a problem in our job. We think about what we want to eat and we feed ourselves. We think about someone we love and we surprise them, in turn making them happy. Positive thoughts typically beget progress. And progress is always the point.</p>

<p>It’s the negative thoughts that trap us. These thoughts and the rubbernecking thoughts they engender are what stymy our progress. So, as our mind trucks along, spit-balling thoughts at us constantly, we can find ourselves either moving forward, <em>in the flow</em>, or we find ourselves in a <em>thought accident</em>, rubbernecking, and now entangled in a traffic jam of absolutely useless thinking.</p>

<p>I’ll never be a good writer. It took me asking my girlfriend to help me remember the word <em>entitlement</em>. For fuck’s sake. I’m an idiot. Look at me…an absolute fucking moron. Ew. Holy shit. <em>Look</em> at me. Is this what I look like? Why is my face so stupid looking? Why the fuck are there hairs in my ears? Why doesn’t anyone tell me I have hairs in my ears?! Obviously, no one tells me because everyone enjoys secretly mocking me. Everyone hates me. And look at this pandemic gut I’ve put on. I’ll never lose this weight. I’ll probably die of diabetes. Or maybe a lions will attack me. Are there lions here in the south? There could be lions here if the zoo lost funding and a disgruntled zookeeper just happened to not lock the cages one night. Then there would be lions. Or, bears. Bears actually live here. Holy fuck…what if sharks could breathe? Fucking great whites walking around on land? But I guess they couldn’t walk, so they’d what, flop around? Still, even if they flopped around, land sharks would definitely kill us all. I’d be first to go. And, I wouldn’t get to apologize to that lady I didn’t hold the door for at the gas station that time in Joshua Tree. I know she still thinks about that. Cursing the day I was born. That’s it! She cursed me. She was a fucking witch, and I didn’t hold the door because I was, fuck what was I doing? So that’s why sharks will learn to breathe and fucking eat us all. Do we have milk? I should probably go get milk.</p>

<p>That’s how negative thinking works. We let one negative thought get our attention and then the rest of our thoughts rubberneck around to the point that we’re stuck, doing absolutely nothing but making ourselves miserable with meaningless non-existences.</p>

<p>Being mindful is the hardest easiest thing to be. Driving is a good example of when we are mindful. We’re present. We’re observing the rules of the road and operating our vehicle safely, <strong>not</strong> driving in the goddamn left lane which is for passing only. For fuck’s sake, who taught you how to drive!? if you’re going to drive slow—meaning <em>less</em> than ten miles over the speed limit—then move your nowhere-going ass over to the right lane…and goddamn it, there I go again; rubbernecking.</p>

<p>Mindfulness is when we’re in a flow. We’re operating without influencing our operation. Like Bruce Lee says, “like water.” In the mindful state, we find our “way around or through” whatever it is we’re coming up against, which is most often ourselves.</p>

<p>However, mindfulness isn’t a one-and-done. Mindfulness is an <em>always</em> practice. The goal isn’t to attain some state. Our mind isn’t a destination. It’s a journey. Alan Watts said, ““To travel is to be alive, but to get somewhere is to be dead.”</p>

<p>Maybe someone out there has achieved perfect mindfulness. I doubt it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Nana korobi,<br />
ya oki</p>

  <p>Fall down seven times,<br />
stand up eight times.<br />
— Japanese proverb</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m certainly still on the path of falling down and getting up again. I’ve accepted that. And that’s made the journey all the more enjoyable; all the more experiential.</p>

<p>Join me.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>About Writing...</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//about-writing</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//about-writing</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Remember, a writer writes, always.”<br />
— Larry; <em>Throw Momma From the Train</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I call bullshit.</p>

<p>Maybe that makes me a terrible writer. I’m certainly unpublished. Hell, unknown for that matter. So, maybe the joke’s on me. Maybe writers <em>do</em> write, <em>always</em>. But, I’m not sure I buy it.</p>

<p>But, then again, what exactly <em>is</em> writing?</p>

<p>Maybe I—maybe <em>we</em>—have it all wrong.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v8ZCX0eywXw">fun and informative interview with Chuck Palahniuk</a>, Joe Rogan asks him about his writing process. (And, leave your opinions about either of these guys at the fucking door—I literally don’t care.) As Chuck goes into his process explaining things the way Chuck does, we observe that Joe is a little confused as Chuck tells him about how he relegates the typing parts of writing to places he feels trapped, like airports. So Joe asks him, “so that’s the only time you actually <em>write-write</em>?” Chuck smiles and answers with something that’s stuck with me ever since, “the <em>keyboarding</em> is not <em>writing</em>.” He expands upon this, but I’ll leave that to your discovery.</p>

<p>So if writing isn’t <em>just</em> the part where we sit at the keyboard and spill scene descriptions and character dialog onto our keys, and languish at how our sentences aren’t remotely as terse and powerful as Cormac McCarthy’s, what exactly <em>is</em> writing?</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/cormac1.jpg" alt="Cormac McCarthy; objectively the greatest writer of all time...and equally as suave." /></p>

<p>For me writing has always been more like observation. I don’t necessarily feel that I’m building a story or creating characters as much as I feel I’m sharing space with them. I’ve been allowed to bear witness. Images fill my mind’s eye, and conversations play between my ears. I’m not making this happen. I’m simply the documentarian.</p>

<p>But like any good documentarian, this process isn’t completely hands-off. It’s certainly my job then to record the goings-on. To paint with words what I see and hear. I do that by taking notes, physical or digital, capturing voice recordings, all in an attempt to translate into words what my mind’s camera and microphone have collected. <em>Is this what it feels like to write a novelization of a film?</em></p>

<p>But, it’s also my job to probe a little.</p>

<p>Characters are people. And people aren’t always forthcoming. Sometimes we have to guide conversations or ask questions to get us to the heart of a thing. Sometimes we have to be the friend/psychotherapist and lead our characters through past experience and trauma.</p>

<p>The same goes for our settings. We can’t write about a house we’ve not explored. We have to open all the doors and cabinets. We have to check behind the paintings on the wall and lift the mattresses in search of hidden things. We have to walk the roads of our characters’ hometowns, fish their rivers, and shop their stores.</p>

<p>So, maybe I’m wrong to scoff at the notion of the “<em>always writing writer</em>.” Maybe we are always writing. Maybe we’ve just allowed the idea of <em>keyboarding</em> to be our vision of what writing means. When I look at it this way, there’s a whole lot more that goes into writing than hitting a daily word count.</p>

<p>The reality is that maybe I—maybe <em>we</em>—need to be more respectful of our process. And understand that, yes, there’s something to the typing, the page <em>does</em> matter, but writing is so much more than that.</p>

<p>And so, while I may not hit a daily word count or some other metric which has attained buzzworthy status among the writers’ social circles, I <em>am</em> writing.</p>

<p><em>We</em> are writing.</p>

<p>So, yes, maybe writers <em>do</em> write, <em>always</em>. It’s just maybe not what we’ve always thought it looks like.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“A writer is a person for whom writing is more difficult than it is for other people.”<br />
— Thomas Mann</p>
</blockquote>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>It's Spooky Season</title>
	  <link>https://deviljames.com//spooky-time</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://deviljames.com//spooky-time</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>“Eye of newt, and toe of frog,<br />
Wool of bat, and tongue of dog,<br />
Adder’s fork, and blind-worm’s sting,<br />
Lizard’s leg, and owlet’s wing,—<br />
For a charm of powerful trouble,<br />
Like a hell-broth boil and bubble.<br />
Double, double toil and trouble;<br />
Fire burn, and caldron bubble.”<br />
― William Shakespeare</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let’s keep this one light.</p>

<p>It’s October 1st.</p>

<p>It’s that most glorious time of the year. When the strangling tendrils of summer’s humidity slink away and in their place the air takes on a crisp bite. When the smells shift to cider and pumpkin. And the leaves shift from greens to hues of orange and red. I can finally wear jeans and hoodies again. (Y’all, it’s fucking hot in the south. And it’s <em>not</em> a dry heat.)</p>

<p>But, most important of all this means it’s time for the mosquitoes to hibernate, or better yet, <strong>DIE</strong>!</p>

<p>Ok, seriously, most importantly it means it’s finally <strong>HALLOWEEN</strong> season!!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="assets/images/halloweenMe.jpg" alt="What the hell even am I?" /></p>

  <p>What the hell even am I? <em><strong>Why</strong></em> do I have the stigmata?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Whatever <em>normal</em> is, I’ve never been that. <em>Obviously</em>. Just look at that picture up there of me a kid. The others? All smiling faces and radiant colors. Me? Some blasphemous scourge shrouded in black all ready to devour little souls—and lots of candy. <em>Honestly</em>, why do I have the stigmata? I need to talk to my mother about this.</p>

<p>If it’s not clear by the provided photographic childhood evidence, I’ve always been obsessed with the spooky and macabre. And I got it honest. My mom would hand down the latest Stephen King novels once she finished reading them. My grandfather would let me sit in on horror and gore movies I was <em>way</em> too young to see.</p>

<p>But a favorite story my mother tells to back this up is of a night she went out and left me with my grandparents. She came home, late, after midnight-ish, and she says the house was dark and quiet save for the TV glowing in the living room. When she walked in, she found me there, wide-eyed, glued to a black-and-white vampire movie while my grandfather snored beside me.</p>

<p>That obsession continues.</p>

<p>I can’t think of a time in my childhood or adolescence that I wasn’t nose deep in a Stephen King (or, yes, Dean Koontz) novel or shoveling popcorn into my mouth while watching the latest—and often, least greatest—horror film. In adulthood, the search for all things horror is at a constant fever pitch. When it comes to horror in film and literature I consider myself a connoisseur. Though, scary fucking weirdo may also be accurate.</p>

<p>For this Halloween season, our first under pandemic conditions, no haunted houses or mazes, or double features at the cinema, I decided to craft us up an at home sixty-one day horror movie marathon. If you’re interested, you can check out the list of films over on my <a href="https://letterboxd.com/writeknuckled/list/2020s-61-days-of-horror/">Letterboxd account</a>, and while you’d be 30 days late to this party, feel free to join in and follow along.</p>

<p>Most of these films I’ve seen before, but I’ve made certain to add some newer and/or unseen classic films to the list. The beautiful thing about this marathon is that my significant other also loves Halloween and “<em>spoopy</em>” things, but she’s not seen even a fraction of the horror canon I have. And one of my favorite things is sharing something I love with someone I love.</p>

<p>I’ve tried to maintain a thread through the films, linking them together in ways that make sense, even if not immediately obvious. One glaring exception is that our first film, <em>An American Werewolf in London</em> is a film we watched out of a bit of “necessity,” meaning it kept popping up in some documentaries we were watching and she continued to comment on it. So, it simply had to be our fist film. From there, we get some of the classic goodies, some zombies, more werewolves, eldrich monsters, aliens, creatures, and witches…and so on.</p>

<p>The first film on the list that will be completely new to me, is quite new to all of us, and that’s <em>Antebellum</em>. I’ve not seen it yet, and while I’ve also not read the book <em>Kindred</em> by Octavia Butler, I’m dumfounded that her name is not listed in the credits. How is this film <em>not</em> based on that book? I guess I’ll have to see the film and read the book and make that assessment for myself.</p>

<p>We’re still trying to find other ways to make up for the lack of overall Halloween-ness this season. I’d love to find some fun socially-distanced things to do with friends and family. Meanwhile, our list of horror movies and decorations are doing well to keep us spirited this season.</p>

<p>But honestly, this is just kind of our normal aesthetic.</p>

<p>It’s always Halloween here.
<img src="assets/images/pumpkin.jpg" alt="John Carpenter's _Halloween_" /></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
